Opa!
Opa! Opa!
Ah... Opa!
Everybody say
- Opa!
Opa!
Opa! Opa!
Mom, do you want some coffee?
That's good, Maria.
Hey!
Oh. How's my mom today?
Hi, Mom. It's me, Toula.
I'm your daughter.
No. My daughter is young and beautiful.
Go do your homework.
We've been discussing
everything with your mother.
Mom? Remember when we were talking
about Toula taking a trip?
I discussed it
with your father last night.
I know he's gone.
I'm not nuts.
He was in my dream.
- You're going to Greece
for the reunion in your father's village.
That's right. And?
Because you promised your father
you would give his journal
to his best friends.
- Yes!
- That's right!
- Mom remembers!
- See? I know. I know.
It's so nice to meet you.
Just kidding.
I know. I know.
All moms pretend they're okay
so the family won't worry.
Because, for a mom,
it's the badge of honor
to take care of everyone,
especially Greek women who give birth,
then immediately get up
and cook everyone family dinner,
while the Greek man stands there
and declares himself
the head of the house.
Since we lost my dad,
the head of the house,
it's been a while without family dinner.
We've been feeling kind of scattered,
which is weird for us,
because my family used to be
stuck together by our own sweat.
That's how an immigrant family survives,
working together, sticking together,
running a restaurant.
But not today.
I am going on a vacation.
We're going to Greece.
- Oh, yeah.
It's Nick.
Hey, Toula, you got Dad's journal, right?
We're doing it, Dad.
Just came to say bye to Ma.
So, Toula, who am I driving with?
Thea Voula and Thea Frieda.
A trip without my kids?
I mean, it's finally "me" time.
I'm gonna look great
when I meet Dad's friends.
I got some grooming to do.
Ma! I need some hair dye!
I got to use your shower!
- Oh!
- Oh, Jesus.
See that?
This will be
our first time in Greece.
My dad never went back.
It's what immigrant parents do.
Work hard, give it all to the kids,
so we can take the trip they never did.
It doesn't seem right.
But my dad asked me to go to the reunion,
find his friends
and give them his journal.
It's his life story.
My dad also told me
I better take some time off
because I was starting to look old.
So...
Vacation!
Welcome to
Chicago International Airport.
- Okay.
- Hello.
Paris, you made it.
Oh! Love the 'do.
- Wow.
- How were finals?
You know, I was thinking
I should stay home.
- What?
- You know?
No. You can see Bennett when you get back.
No. No, no, no. That's over. That's done.
Oh, Roscoe now. Right, right.
No, Aristotle. Thea Voula set you up.
- Yeah, which is why that is over, too.
I just... I wanted to study this summer.
Just take a break from your perfect GPA.
You put too much pressure on yourself.
It's Greece.
For Pappou. Pappou.
"Give me a word, any word,
"and I show you how the root
of that word is Greek."
"Nachos."
Heh.
The family came to say goodbye.
- Everyone?
- Yeah.
It says maximum 20 people.
That's six Greeks.
Everyone, suck it in.
- I got it.
Oh, man.
Hey, snacks.
You can't afford since you got fired.
Retired.
Eh, a Greek man retires
a week after he is dead.
Hey, good one. Come on.
What's that?
- Let's go over the restaurant.
- I got my kids on shifts.
I ordered the beef.
I ordered the fish.
- Take care of my mom.
We will.
- You're good cousins.
- I am.
- We got to go! Bye!
Bye! Bye! Bye! Bye!
- Bye!
Bye!
Flight 204
departing for Athens.
Is every Greek in Chicago on this plane?
Everyone going to the homeland, sit down!
Ah, big family trip.
Aunt Voula.
I'm in charge. You report to me.
Wha...
I found my bikini from 1972.
Oh.
Who wants souvlaki?
Homemade.
I made it.
Paging Sue Vlaki.
Anybody by the name of Sue Vlaki
on this flight?
Take this evil eye to protect you.
Yeah, you know I don't believe
in the Greek voodoo.
That's why you're still single.
We found out we're related
to Alexander the Great.
Me, too.
- Hey!
Hey. All right.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a minute, Ian.
Where you going?
Your seat's back there, right?
We're trying to have
a little fun here, okay?
I'm fun.
When?
It doesn't matter, Ian, 'cause I need
to try and get some sleep.
The big button.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain.
Please take your seats and make sure
your seatbelts are securely fastened.
We are ready for takeoff.
Oh, good! My assistant is here.
- Family documents.
- The family?
Paris?
Aristotle! What...
- I didn't know you were gonna be here.
- ...are you doing here?
Your Thea Voula hired me
to help her on a trip.
I didn't know that you were gonna be here.
That's right, they know each other.
What a coincidence.
Such a nice Greek boy.
They had an amazing date.
She ghosted him.
Why can't this family
respect my boundaries?
- Boundaries?
I can't get any space.
You want space, you got it.
Forget I'm here. You won't even see me.
- Can we switch?
- No. Sit down.
Make up. Make out.
That's Aristotle.
I have to switch seats with Paris.
I knew...
- Let them work it out.
Oh.
Something else is going on with Paris.
Don't. It's none of our business.
Oh. We are so different.
You must sit down!
Or we are not going to Greece.
Sit.
Ah. Yeah.
Welcome to Athens, Greece.
"Coppertone," written in Greek.
I mean...
- Oh, man.
Why haven't we done this before?
Uh, hello to everyone
I haven't met. I'm Aristotle.
Car rental is this way.
- Actually, I think it's this way.
- Very smart.
- No, no, no, no, I think they said...
You came!
You are the Portokalos family.
I sent you the invitation.
I'm the mayor of your father's village.
Welcome to the reunion!
We are related
through your pappou's pappou,
who was a twin
and married to my great-great yiayia's
sister's sister-in-law.
- Cousin!
- Hey!
- Oh! Cousin!
Oh, my God.
I'm Victory.
Aunt Voula. I will be your favorite.
Frappé, iced coffee, Greek style.
Thank you. Do you have decaf?
Sopa. You're in Greece now.
I'll try it.
Ah, what's happening?
- What's "sopa" mean?
- It kind of means "shush."
It means "shut up."
Okay. This way to the car.
- Come.
- Shotgun.
No!
- Come on, I got it.
- This way.
Come on, everyone.
Whoo!
Are you okay about Aristotle on the trip?
Let me live my life. Okay?
- Cousin.
- Yeah?
- You drive.
- No!
I've never been to Greece.
I'll give you directions.
Looking good, mori.
Victory?
How many people are you expecting
at the reunion?
Come on, come on. We need music!
I love this song. Number one. The best.
Everybody, sing!
Toula, go straight.
The city of Athens.
Hey, do we have time to stop there?
No.
Toula, turn left.
The ancient Parthenon.
Are we going there today?
No.
Ah.
The Olympic stadium.
Could we...
No.
From here,
a short boat ride to the island.
Can we see the island from here?
No.
Don't slow down.
We're going to miss the boat.
Is that a beach?
Oh, can we go swimming?
Yes.
Time for a swim!
- We have to get to the village.
- Sopa!
- Go fast, or we will miss the boat.
- Okay.
Whoo! Whoo!
Whoo!
Come on, Toula.
Opa! Opa! Opa!
It's like we've gone back in time.
My daughter is divorced two times.
My son is gay.
Okay.
So I understand alternative lifestyles.
I like your fashion look.
Do you like to wear
boy clothes or girl clothes?
- Both and neither.
- Ah.
- How about you?
- Depends on the day.
I like you.
Everybody does.
All my life, I had a bone in my hip
that stuck out
like a toothpick in an olive.
Touch it.
Olive groves.
People from many countries
working the harvest.
And some people from our village
work there, too,
because our olive groves don't have water.
But I have a plan to bring them back.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Because I love our village.
I love Greece!
Number one. The best.
Whoo!
That's it.
That's my dad's village.
Everybody out!
We need a picture for Mom.
Oh, here we are.
- Okay, ready?
- Thea Frieda, I have your neck.
- Pull. Pull. Pull.
- Okay.
- High. High.
- Neck?
-  There we are.
I've got this.
- Relax your lips.
- Yeah.
"I'm so mad at the camera."
Now... blow it away.
- Blow it away.
Supermodels. Is fantastic.
Number one. The best.
- I'm gonna send this to Mom.
- I go now to rest.
Okay... Victory?
Wh... Where's Victory?
Every village has its hidden passages.
Like a maze, because of centuries
of invading countries and wars.
Follow me.
Right up here.
This way.
Come, come.
No, this way.
Okay.
Where is everyone?
Maybe they're at work.
No, it's something bad.
- Jesus!
Yes.
What'd she say?
"I was just a chin hair away
from being your mother."
I had no idea
Pappou's village was so nice.
Hey, don't talk about it.
It's bad luck.
No restaurants or hotels open, guys.
Let's go to where
your mother and me grew up.
Mykonos knows how to party.
Can we go to Mykonos?
We're here for the reunion.
Then we're going drinking?
How old do you think this tree is?
Let me see.
Uh, 98 years and seven months.
Chest height, 2.11,
multiplied by diameter.
- Dendrochronology.
- Greek word.
Our dad talked about this square.
Our dad played here
with his three best friends,
Thanasis, Dimos, and George.
Hmm. Your grandfather talked about
a freshwater spring
flowing down from the mountain.
Women would fill jugs.
We only saw that one woman, though.
- Who?
She was angry.
Who was angry?
-  Oi!
Jesus. Where does she come from?
Hello, Constantinos.
It's good to see you again.
Um, hello, but no.
No, I'm... I'm Nikos Portokalos.
I'm Constantine's son.
We lost our dad late last year.
Do you know which house was his?
Gone. Fire.
Come.
Follow me down this dark alley.
Oh, cool.
So no one will find our bodies.
I am Alexandra.
I am making soup.
Yeah, this is where it ends.
Get the eggs.
Chairs. Bowls.
Oh, nobody feeds these ones?
Eat. Eat.
- That's why she has no breasts...
- Oh. Oh.
...and he has no kolo.
Okay. No, no. Good.
Thank you. That's good. That's good.
- Why? Okay, thank you.
- Ah!
What does your husband hold on to?
Everybody needs a love handle.
I smell food.
Don't talk about it. It's bad luck.
Oh, my...
Welcome.
My helper, Qamar.
- She lives with me.
- Hi.
- She's like a daughter to me.
Aw.
- An orphan from Syria.
- Oh.
Say hello. We are not xenophobic.
- Greek word.
- Yes, we know. We are Greeks.
Hi.
- Hi.
Oh. Little friend.
You're studying... Ah, philosophy.
Invented by the Greeks.
Again, we know.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. You?
I study chemistry.
- Get the bread.
Nice.
I have something for you.
- Hope you like it.
- Hot! Ah!
You never reached into a fire?
Ah, that's so nice.
- Yes, in my culture, we give gifts.
- Oh.
How did you get this?
Uh, the mayor sent it.
- Who?
- Victory.
Oh. Only one person voted... Victory...
So Victory's the mayor.
A win is a win.
What did you do?
It is my plan for the village regrowth.
All the people who moved away years ago?
I invited them for a reunion.
They will remember how beautiful it is,
and they will move back,
and the village will go great again.
See? I'm a good mayor.
How many people live here?
- Lots.
- Six.
Six is a lot.
Who came for the reunion?
- You.
And?
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
We came all this way to give
something very important
to my father-in-law's friends.
Now you're saying nobody's here?
Whoa, Dad.
Not catastrophe. Is fantastic.
Don't worry.
You know, it's... It's been a long day.
I'll... I'll call us a cab.
I'm also the town taxi driver.
But no.
You will all sleep
in the biggest house in the village.
No one lives there now.
No, we're gonna go to that hotel.
If you want to insult us.
We would love to stay.
- No Wi-Fi.
- Yeah.
The stairs are out.
That's... There's...
There's no other bedrooms.
Hey, one room all together
is how our dad grew up.
Yeah.
Hey, guys, this is gonna be fun.
Family sleepover!
I can do facials with Greek yogurt.
Enemas, too.
Pass.
Flavored yogurt or plain, Thea?
Always the fruit.
"Give her space" doesn't mean try harder.
No, I'm not a creep,
and, uh, she's not into nerds.
Nerds win, Aristotle.
Were you a nerd?
No.
Women, they just want us to hear 'em,
and we should listen
'cause they got a lot to teach us.
But then you get married, and they try
and strangle you in your sleep.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
- We did that!
- We lit a fire!
- We just did that!
Oh, it looks great in here.
- Oh, okay.
- There we are.
Okay, there it is.
Hey, Thea, we lit a fire.
Oh! Bravo.
We did it. We...
Bravo, Niko, Aristotle.
Very manly.
But don't brag. It's bad luck.
Ugh! "Don't cross your legs in church.
It's bad luck."
"Don't give an empty wallet as a gift.
Don't make fun of your aunts.
It's bad luck.
Ian. Ian.
What? What? What?
There was a man.
Uh...
He was right there, a man.
- What'd he look like?
- Ah, I didn't really see him,
but, like, handsome, piercing eyes.
- Handsome?
- Yeah. Right there.
Oh. Oh!
- Hey.
- Mmm.
Have sex on Easter like everyone else.
This is nice. Anybody cold?
No, so don't yell at anybody.
That was epic.
I yelled before.
Sopa.
Well, it's not what we expected,
but we made it to Greece, yeah?
- Yeah. This is good.
- Mmm-hmm.
Well, let's hit the hay, I guess.
I am not tired.
Oh, you drank, like, ten frappé coffees.
- Oh, I'm fine.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Okay.
Let's go, too.
We are going
to the best dance club.
Is it close?
No.
We need drinks.
Welcome.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Christos!
Qamar's boyfriend!
But his father wants him to marry a Greek.
So it's a secret.
Secrets are a waste of time.
In this life, be open about what you want.
- I want to go dance.
Mmm!
Whoo!
So...
Oh, no, no.
No, no, no, no. Uh...
Well, I... I don't really know him.
- You will end up together.
- What?
Enjoy the dance to that moment.
And, you, dance with me.
- Okay.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey.
Hey.
So, uh...
This got weird.
- I'm sorry, I...
- No, no. I'm sorry, okay?
- This year was rough for me.
- You don't have to explain anything.
Ever.
Let's make the best
of the rest of the vacation.
In a remote Greek village
inhabited by ghosts and anger.
Let's do it.
Come on. Come on.
What is it? What's happening?
- Shoo!
I thought my husband
came back from the dead.
Hey!
Someone's loud truck
woke me up last night!
Hey!
Is she gone?
Great news.
The grandfather of my friend
received the reunion invitation.
Oh. He's dead.
My dad's best friends.
Thanasis, Dimos, and George.
- I know them.
- Oh! Do they still live here?
- No.
- How do we find them?
They will come for the reunion.
- Did they tell you they're coming?
- No.
Aristotle! Groceries.
How did it go?
Ugh.
Oh, look.
Where did she come from?
Handmade purses and shoes!
Oh! The big city.
I'm going to shop till you drop.
Fresh watermelon. Look.
There we are.
Come this way.
Over here.
Hopefully, someone will know
my dad's friends.
So, you are giving me
the best cheese
and the fattest beans, yes?
Of course.
Oh, thank you.
We buy from them, they give to us.
Thank you.
Cheers.
Ah.
Hmm.
Mmm, good.
Do you know where these men moved to?
- From the village of Vrisi.
- No.
- Drink.
- Okay.
Thea, I didn't sleep last night,
and I can't really day-drink like this.
Don't worry, don't worry.
A lady is never drunk.
-  Cheers.
- Okay.
Do you know these men,
and where they moved to?
- Drink.
Cheers.
Cheers. Cheers.
Drink.
Cheers.
- You want some wet cheese?
Sure.
Hey, is there a shower?
There.
It's not warm.
Eh, not a problem.
Hey, Victory.
Did you hear from my dad's friends?
As the mayor, I promise
you did not travel here for no reason.
They will come soon.
Where's the oldest tree
in this entire area?
Is it the one in the olive grove?
- Ask Alexandra.
- No.
- Pretty cool, huh?
- Yeah, yeah, it is.
And by the way, there's a shower
right there if you need one.
- Ha!
- Thanks, man.
Nick!
Oh.
Pick the one we have for dinner.
Oh, thank you.
Uh, I'm a vegetarian.
No.
Which way's the path to the sea?
Oh, thank you.
Hey, Thea.
Is this a memorial?
Yeah. So many wars.
My dad never talked about that stuff.
Getting through those years
made him strong.
Afraid of nothing.
Yeah.
That's Greek men.
- Hide.
- Oh.
Scooch over.
I will ask around. Here.
Drink!
Don't worry. A lady is never drunk.
Oh...
I have never seen my mom drink
anything more than communion wine.
- They were thirsty.
Whee!
I ate a bug!
Come!
Oh. Ah, Paris! That's good.
There they are!
Victory!
Hand these out.
Oh, thank you. Okay.
- Alexandra, that's for you.
- Here you go.
Ah. Hi.
- Hey.
- Hi! Oh, I saw that guy again.
What guy? You...
- You been drinking?
- Yeah.
The handsome guy who was
outside the window last night.
I saw him today.
It's kind of weird. Hey, listen.
- Want to go make out in the chicken coop?
- What?
I need sugar for my bougatsa.
- Hey, Toula.
- Uh?
Is this family dinner?
It is.
Nice.
- You find Dad's friends?
- Uh...
- Soon.
- Okay. Listen to me, Toula.
- You're gonna find them. Okay?
- Yeah.
- You're gonna find them.
- Okay.
You're a good cook.
- I'm a good cook, too.
- Maybe better.
- Oh.
Right here.
Go.
We should invite the six villagers.
I'll ask them.
I'm cooking! Wear your eating pants!
Yep.
I'm so mad at the camera.
Now blow it away.
Whoo!
Supermodels. Fantastic.
Number one. The best.
Why haven't you made your move?
We decided to be friends.
"Decided to be friends"
is for when you find out
that you're dating a cousin.
Company's coming.
You're drunk.
- You are.
- Yeah.
That's him.
That's the man from last night.
- Hello.
- Alexandra's son.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Ah, Alexandra's son.
Mystery solved.
Why is he looking at you?
What... Why are you smiling?
I'm not.
Yes, you are.
"He's so handsome."
That's the way you described him.
-  I did?
- Yeah.
So I can't look at a handsome man
who's clearly attracted to me?
I'm your brother.
Sopa.
Brother?
Yes.
- So not attracted to Toula?
- Nick.
Got it. Wait.
What's happening?
I was with your father
before he left the village
and met your mother.
Your father never knew this is our son,
Peter.
And this is my son, Christos.
Hello.
All right.
Opa.
Crazy!
- Wow!
Oh, my God.
Yes, family!
Oh, you carried this burden alone.
It was my secret to keep.
Secrets are a waste of time.
-  Cheers!
A toast to living your truth.
Yeah, and, hey, well,
Qamar and Christos are dating.
- Oh.
-  Yeah.
What?
We never wanted you to find out this way.
I don't want you to think badly of me.
But we're in love.
Who wants bougatsa?
- I'll take a bite of that.
- Maybe a bite, yeah.
- Yes, right.
- Yeah.
Yes. Yeah, sorry.
Uh, but, do you know where he lives now?
No, no, no...
Not the father, the grandfather.
Yes. Tell him about the reunion.
"Welcome to the reunion."
It's at the end of the week.
Is anyone gonna show?
Everything will be wonderful.
Like last night.
Great party.
It was a catastrophe
and kind of your fault
for proposing a toast.
That is what makes me fun.
Oh, how's your head?
Like it's on too tight.
What's he trimming?
What do you think?
Upstairs or downstairs?
Oh, man.
So, Toula, Peter's pretty mad
about Qamar not being Greek.
Hey. I'm a non-Greek in this family.
Turned out okay.
Did it?
Another brother.
My mind is blown.
Yeah. My mind is blowing in the wind, too.
I am surprised, but I am not surprised,
because I'm never surprised.
You lost me.
So, Toula, do we tell Mom about Peter?
No.
Are you gonna tell your sister
about her late husband's son?
Frieda, you know me.
I'm sorry. I know you're not a gossip.
I am not a gossip. I'm a tattletale.
I already called her.
- Hey, Toula, your phone.
Hey, it's Athena.
- Hey.
Hi.
We have a brother?
Your mom is right here.
We told her about Peter.
Hello.
Hi, Mom.
So...
Your father has a son
that he didn't know about?
Well...
it was a long time ago.
We always have room
for more love in this family.
And you tell Peter
I can't wait to meet him.
Oh. And say hello to his mother.
I'll bet her name is Alexandra.
It is.
Well, your father
talked in his sleep.
What were we talking about?
Hello? No, it's me, Nick, your son.
I... I know. I know.
I know.
We love you, Mom. It's okay.
We love you, Ma.
Talk to you later.
Bye.
- It's okay.
- Yeah.
I used your recipe.
Not enough mizithra.
Oh, wow, look at this.
Great.
- Hot cheese! Hot cheese.
- Oh!
Number one.
The best.
So, we take them from here.
We separate the leaves from olives.
What happened to the fountain
in our village?
Why is it dry?
The rockslide cut off the spring.
Don't start with me. I'll get to it.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
- Yep. No, no!
Hold... Hold up!
My son,
we lost his mother, but he stayed strong.
He's a smart kid.
He earned a degree
in sustainable agriculture.
This country needs his brain.
Instead, he's wasting
his time dating a xeni.
A xeni!
Eat something, Peter. You'll feel better.
Hey, do you know where
the oldest tree in the area is?
My dad...
Our dad,
when he used to talk to me about it,
he told me he used to
sit underneath it and dream.
Do you know where it is?
No.
- Ask my mother.
- No.
Hey. Is your head still caving in?
Yeah.
Come on, take a walk with me.
I'm gonna go hang with a monk.
- A monk?
- Yeah.
I can't.
I really need
to find my dad's friends.
Hi.
- Hey.
Sorry about last night.
I forgot there was alcohol in alcohol.
For the record,
I was not attracted to you.
- Hmm. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got it.
- Hmm?
So, uh... this was our dad's.
It's a journal he kept from the time
he went to America.
Do you think that any of these invitations
reached the older people
that live in other cities?
No. Stop trying.
Well, I'm gonna keep looking everywhere.
Thanks, Toula.
You got it.
- Bye.
Oh. Right there. See that?
You have many children.
Yeah. But none of them
listen to me, you know?
But, hey, I go with it. I learn.
You must know,
a tree that bends is stronger
than the tree that breaks.
I think the saying is,
"The tree that won't bend
breaks in the wind."
No, I think it's,
"The windless tree bends from breaking."
What the hell is a windless tree?
What do you mean, Peter? Come on.
A windless tree doesn't move,
like a stubborn Greek father.
That's a bad metaphor.
Now, let's talk about your son.
Ah, I'm sorry I don't speak more Greek.
But I know "efharisto."
Oh. Very good.
We were given all these things,
and I'd like to give them to you,
if you don't mind.
Of course I don't mind.
"Regift" is a Greek word.
- There you go.
If Victory's plan works,
and people move back to the village,
Qamar and I will run this
as an organic farm,
exporting products to the world.
That is our life plan.
Whoa.
What's yours?
Uh...
I'm hoping my roommate gets swapped out.
He... steals my waters and floss.
So, you know, he's kind of a drag.
Uh, Paris?
You know, jump in.
Uh...
Um...
You...
I just remembered,
I don't want to be here right now.
I suck.
I cannot fulfill the one thing
my dad ever asked me to do.
Actually, he asked you to do a lot, Toula.
- Right?
- Mmm-hmm.
-  Like, every day.
- Yeah.
Oh, my God, so much.
But this is big.
You know, I promised him.
It's been a hard year, huh.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Both our dads.
Now I have another brother.
My mom.
That's hard.
I just wonder how she feels, you know?
How she... If she's afraid.
- And something's up with Paris.
- Oh, no, no.
- You...
- No. No.
- You two...
- Hey.
What's this say?
What, that? That's the word "Syros."
It's an island here.
- Where'd you get this?
- From my friend, the monk.
I think it's a list of all
the older people that moved away.
And where they moved to.
What?
It's all here.
Thanasis and Dimos and George.
I love you so much.
- I have to call Nikki.
- Hey.
- Hey, hey.
I heard you have a hot older brother.
- How's the reunion?
- There isn't one.
All of Gus' friends moved far away.
Thanasis Papagianopoulos went to Syros.
Dimos Ginakes went to Paros.
George Diacos went to Rhodes.
So, Nikki, you were on Syros
last summer, right?
Yeah, yeah. Uh... I know Syros and Paros.
Yeah, and actually,
Patrick and me, we did five islands.
Okay.
Could you both make some calls
and see if anyone can get
the message to these three men
about the reunion?
Yeah, sure. I know
eight or nine people right off the bat.
- No problem.
- Yeah, Angelo and I are on it.
Okay...
- Okay, bye.
- You did that!
- Yeah.
Flight 235
departing for Athens.
So, do you think anyone else
is coming to this reunion?
Thea Voula, can we change our tickets
to stay longer?
No, we flew on the points.
Oh. Hi.
Dad! Oh! Can you please...
Can you just give me some privacy?
Mmm-mmm.
Come here.
Look at that view.
Oh!
This is beautiful.
My dad grew up with all this
and no food.
But he built a great life. He worked hard.
Really hard.
Let's not do that.
We never came to Greece.
We never took a real vacation.
We should be having fun.
We should be on a vacation.
- Come on.
- Let's have some fun while we can.
I'm just gonna try Nikki one more time.
- Hey.
Hi!
Did you find my dad's friends?
Don't worry. Oh.
Got to go.
Oh.
Welcome to Athens, Greece.
Hi.
"Soov" or "comfort table"?
Comfort table.
Departing
for the island of Syros.
Now arriving
on the island of Syros.
Exit from the rear of the boat.
Hey. We partied last summer.
Nikki!
Can you help us find a man named
Thanasis Papagianopoulos?
He's about 80 years old,
and he comes from the town of Vrisi.
We'll find him.
Yeah.
- Uh, from Angelo.
"Don't worry. We got you."
Hey. It's gonna be okay.
You're gonna get the journal
to your dad's friends.
- Yes.
- Something's going on with Paris,
- but we're gonna let her work it out.
- No.
Thanasis?
We'll find him.
Hey.
You ready for the reunion on Saturday?
Victory... no one's coming.
Yes, they are,
and we are going to have a party.
Good, good.
Because Qamar and I are getting married.
Say what now?
That's fantastic!
So the wedding is on Saturday.
No reunion?
I don't know.
- Now I have to tell my mother.
- No.
A Greek mother goes through life
with two emotions,
"I love you so much,"
and "Why don't you love me
as much as I love you?"
- Hey!
- Where does she come from?
- Oh, come on.
You're letting them get married!
She's a refugee!
With respect, Yiayia, she's an immigrant.
Like the Ukrainians
in the town you give food to.
Like Pappou to America.
You kept a secret from your family.
- What's funny?
- Okay.
You're terrifying.
Uh, it's just that...
Ian and I once kept a secret
from our parents, too.
As did you from yours.
I quit my job as a busboy
and pretended to go to work for two weeks.
I used to smoke.
I failed my entire first year of college.
- You win.
- You what?
Hang on. You failed?
We trusted you to go to NYU,
and you blew it?
What happened?
Sheltered life, got her freedom,
partied her face off.
Come on, it happens.
You two used to make out in the car
like badgers tearing apart a bag of Oreos.
Thea Voula.
Taki and I used to make out so much,
my face is still chapped.
- Thea Voula.
- Here, feel my chin.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Now I got to call the dean.
No, I will get myself through this.
Like I did.
You don't need my permission
to get married.
We are getting married.
I give you my permission.
Oh, we are family now.
You look Greek.
- And you look Syrian.
- Ooh!
Everybody, sing!
We have to let her handle it.
That's what I told you.
Really?
Oh, man.
What did you do?
I don't want details.
Just one detail.
We have work to do.
Oh, Christos, the theas, you come with me.
And, Toula... Toula, you...
Take a vacation.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Let's do it!
Yes, yes.
You go away and do it, you little badgers.
Okay, we'll be back to help later.
I want to know everything.
Beautiful.
Ah!
Thanasis Papagianopoulos?
Do you know where Dimos and George are?
Why did you feel the need
to go to all these parties?
Because I had never been
to a party before.
What's that, Nick?
Nothing.
This is the oldest tree?
Yeah.
Okay, Toula just got back.
Don't say anything or she'll kill me.
I probably broke some international law
by transferring this urn, but...
Can you keep a secret?
No.
Peter.
Peter!
Toula, I heard you're back.
Look.
I thought you should know.
- Hey!
Ha!
What are you doing?
I can't tell you, 'cause you'll say no!
Thea Frieda.
How did he get here?
Nick.
Do you know what my brother is up to?
Hmm.
I'm not asking you to gossip.
Okay, good. It's not gossip, it's a fact.
When we lost your father,
your brother asked me
the process to bury him in Greece.
Okay.
I will put this koufeta under your pillow
so you dream about who you will marry.
No more voodoo, okay?
Also, there's other things
for Greek kids to do
rather than just get married
and make Greek babies, you know.
- Some do.
- And I respect their choice.
What are you going to do about college?
Can we please not discuss it?
No. That's not what we do.
We yell and scream.
We find a solution together
using threats and guilt.
I don't think we yelled enough. Hmm-hmm.
Trust me, you can't make me feel
any worse than I already feel.
That's not a meal.
Come.
I baked a goat.
Everybody, listen to Thea Frieda.
Come on, we got to move these rocks.
All right, this is gonna work.
We're ready to go.
- Okay, pull.
Where's the urn?
Hidden!
- Pull!
Keep pulling! Keep pulling!
Run!
Grab it! Grab it! Look at this!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
We are finally ready for the wedding.
Wait. Shouldn't we take this down?
Sopa.
This is the Syrian dabke.
- Everybody!
Whoo! Everybody, listen!
Follow me to find groom this way,
and follow Aristotle and Paris
to find bride that way.
Let's do it!
Let's do it! Hey!
Whoo-hoo!
Looking good, mori.
We came for the reunion!
Who's that?
We are here for the reunion!
I did it.
Cousin!
- Cousin!
You asked me to find the men.
I found everyone.
What did you do?
What are you doing here?
Thanasis, Dimos, and George?
Everybody!
This way!
We are now going to dance
a traditional Greek dance.
All men, come dance the Hasapia!
And all the women,
please come join us
or the traditional Syrian Samah!
You dreamt about Aristotle last night.
How did you know?
I put koufeta under your pillow.
Greek voodoo.
Bam!
Why don't you go dance?
I'll hold your bag for you.
Mmm-mmm.
How much do you know?
All of it.
You planned to use
this ash-neutralizing kit
to bury Dad in Greece.
No, no, no, beside Dad's favorite tree
so he could grow into an olive tree.
I mean, it's got seeds in it,
and I was planning on taking
half the urn back to Mom.
It's not your decision to make.
It's Mom's.
Mom can't make that type
of decision right now,
and you know that, Toula.
Okay, see, the problem is
there's no head of the family anymore.
Don't say that.
No, no, I'm saying it
'cause it's supposed to be you.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
But Athena's the oldest.
Athena's got, like, six kids!
And we decided you had the time.
Oh. Okay.
Well, it's supposed to be Peter, then.
Peter. Peter's too busy, too, Toula.
No.
You know, I'm calling it.
I'm calling it.
- You're calling it?
- I am.
You got us back to Greece.
You got Dad's book back to his friends.
And, well,
you're the head of the family now.
Hey, Nick...
You got Dad back to Greece.
- I did.
- So you're the head of the family.
- Can we share it?
- Yeah, okay, we'll share it.
- Can you hold family dinners?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- I'm not doing them alone!
- You have to help me cook.
- I'll help.
- I will.
- Then fine.
You know...
sometimes Mom remembers,
even if it's just for a few moments.
And that's enough, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, Nick?
This kit, it's for cremated pets.
Oh. Yeah, I see the dog now.
Yeah, I thought it was a bush.
- It's a dog.
- Looks like a bush.
Yeah.
You know what? You're right.
I am?
Do you want to dance?
Aristotle, you...
You don't want to date me, okay?
I'm a mess.
Now you know why
I didn't answer you all year.
Because I was partying...
Me, the perfect, nice Greek girl.
Okay? I blew it.
I want to do well in college.
That is my life plan.
But the philosopher Aristotle once said,
"Educating the mind
without educating the heart
"is no education at all."
Okay, you are so Greek.
Come on.
I... I have to fix my life.
Let's get some air.
Opa!
Hey, hey.
It's... It's okay.
Here's my proposal.
Can we take this slow?
Yeah.
You can text me.
Okay.
I just might.
No babies until you graduate from college
and you buy your parents a house.
Greek aunties. Better than dating apps.
They won't stay.
I know.
I was thinking...
The migrants in the area,
they could live in these empty houses.
Maybe you are a good mayor after all.
Yes!
I said "maybe."
I'm a good mayor, yes?
- Number one. The best.
- Hey, keep it.
Thank you for everything.
Cousin.
- Hi!
I think my dad knew
how much we needed to go on this trip,
to bring us together
and help each other
with the changes that life brings.
We went to a reunion to bring
my dad's story to his friends.
We didn't know a part of his life
would be coming home with us.
Hey, Ian.
Yeah, so where you at? I can't see you.
I'm right behind you. Turn around.
Well, behind me where?
I still can't see you.
Maybe that's not you. Wave your arms.
- I'm waving.
- Jump up and down.
Oh, it's so crowded.
Make a donkey sound.
Hee-haw!
- Louder.
- Hee... haw.
You're outside, aren't you?
Told you I'm fun.
I guess we will never know
who is now the head of the family,
so we'll argue about it... loudly.
And the fact is, it doesn't
really matter who's in charge,
as long as we're together.
Okay, listen, wait. I say we go get Ma,
and then maybe we can have
a family dinner.
- Toula's cooking.
- Hey.
Say it.
Wear your eating pants!
- Yeah!
Yeah.
Stuck together by our own sweat.
Oli mazi, oli mazi
We are all together
It doesn't matter where we are
We're always close, we're never far
From each other
Mmm, mmm
'Cause I'm with you everywhere
Good to know we're always there
For one another
Mmm, mmm
Love will always always, always find a way
And all I, all I, all I wanna say
Oli mazi
We, we are all together in this life
Zoe
Oli mazi
Free, free to be whoever we wanna be
We're one family
Oli mazi
Oh, oh, oh, oh
It doesn't matter what you do
You're here for me I'm here for you
And that's forever. That's forever
Mmm, mmm
'Cause I know you got my back
And I got yours, we both know that
There's nothing better
Mmm, mmm
Love will always
always, always save the day
And all I, all I, all I wanna say
Oli mazi
We, we are all together in this life
Zoe
Oli mazi
Free, free to be whoever we wanna be
We're one family
Oli mazi
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Oli mazi, oli mazi
We are all together. We are all together
Everybody say, "Oli mazi"
Oli mazi
We are all together.
We are all together
Oli mazi
We, we are all together
We, we are all together in this life
Zoe
Oli mazi
Free, free to be whoever we wanna be
We're one family
Oli mazi
Oh, oh, oh, oh